## **ALEX VALLADARES**

South Plainfield, New Jersey 07080 | (201) 686-0997 | <u>Alex.valla101@gmail.com</u> https://github.com/valla101 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-valladares-833903140/

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Analyst with experience in collecting and presenting data for the purpose of quantifying and simplifying raw data. Strengths include HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, ETL, and Tableau. Possesses skills to work on back end and front end of full stack applications. Currently responsible for maintaining equipment and coordinating work with three Port Authority of NY/NJ facilities.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming & Databases: Python, SQL, Tableau, JavaScript (HTML/CSS), VBA, ETL, AWS

PLC Programming: Schneider Electric Unity Pro, Vijeo Citect (SCADA Software)

Misc: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access

#### **PROJECTS**

# Fantasy Premier League Stats Visualization | <a href="https://github.com/valla101/FPL\_Stats\_Visualization">https://github.com/valla101/FPL\_Stats\_Visualization</a> | <a href="https://github.com/valla101/FPL\_Stats\_Visualization">https://github.com/

Full Stack Application that is tracking player statistics for the English Premier League. Geared towards Fantasy
Premier League players, it allows users to compare important statistics between two professional soccer players
by generating bar graphs and tables based on filters. Completed both front & back end aspects of application as
a personal project.

Technologies used: Python, JSON Requests, Pandas, PostgreSQL, Flask, JavaScript, CSS, Heroku

# NBA Awards Predictor | https://github.com/RU-DataScience-Group5/BasketballML

• Full Stack Application that references player statistics since 1980. A Machine Learning Model was developed to determine this season's Most Valuable Player and Rookie of The Year. Contributed with developing Flask routes, front end styling and user interaction.

Technologies used: Python, Pandas, PostgreSQL, Flask, SciKit Learn, JavaScript, AWS Database...

## Vacation Planner using Google API | https://github.com/valla101/python\_api\_challenge

 Generated a Map of Hotels based on a client's Ideal Weather Conditions using Google Maps. Gathered Data from CitiPi, Open Weather API, Google Maps API.

Technologies used: Python, Google Maps API, OpenWeather API, Pandas, JSON Requests, Numpy, CitiPi.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **New Jersey Institute of Technology**

September 2012 – December 2016

B.S. Mechanical Engineering

#### **Rutgers University**

February 2020 – August 2020

Coding Bootcamp - Data Science

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Kapsch TrafficCom - Secaucus, NJ

April 2019 - Present

Field Service Technician

- Troubleshooting & Maintaining on low voltage (DC) devices and PLC Electrical Panels
- HMI configuration with Vijeo Citect for SCADA system
- PLC Software Configuration using Schneider Electric's Unity Pro

- Data Communications Analysis
- On-site commissioning of SCADA System at World Trade Center

# All American Poly - Piscataway, NJ

**April 2018 – March 2019** 

# Maintenance Engineer

- Document and organize inventory system (Fiix) for all assets and spare parts including motors, belts, bearings, and motor drives
- Use lean methodology to improve the longevity of parts and reduce scrap
- Develop Return on Investment for any potential new equipment
- Troubleshoot with PLC's